Abhishek Saini

IOS Developer

Phone: 8860655674

Email: abd17saini@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/abhishek-saini-7ba26a179/

iOS Developer having 8 months of experience in application development and Swift Programming. Knowledge of working in a scrum framework and working with multiple teams. Background in Information Technology and practical programming skills, a self-motivated and a good team player.

RELEVANT SKILLS



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

InfoEdge - Jeevansathi

location: Noida, UP

iOS Developer

December 2021-Present

Wipro

Associate Analyst

October 2021 – November 2021

- Configuring and testing Wipro Proprietary Total Benefit Administration (TBA) System to meet the needs of our clients' requirements.
- Configure tables/parameters in the TBA System as defined by analysis.
- Worked on Defect Management & Analysis and SAS.

Cppsecrets

C++ Developer Intern

December 2018–February 2019

- Develop reader config library in C++.
- Publish brief articles on their website.

The Spark Foundation

September 2020-October 2020

- Code algorithm on task to predict the outcomes. Work on Supervised and Unsupervised Learning.
- Analyse the problem using different Machine Learning algorithms.

Jeevansathi IOS Application

March 2022-Present

- Worked on converting design wireframes into functional pages with Xcode using XIB, Storyboard, and Auto-layout.
- Worked on designing custom components that could be reused across the application.
- Integrated REST web services to connect the iOS application with the backend services.
- Worked on multiple modules in the application. Eg: Registration, Desired Partner Preferences.
 - Registration:
 - Screen Tracking Sending user activity to backend service.
 - Worked on handling complete/incomplete cycle of registration pages.
 - Handling of pages display order.
 - Worked on handling auto-login for the existing users and Data management for the same.
 - Desired Partner Preference :
 - Create a custom drop-down list e.g. Bottomsheet.
 - Implemented caste selection logic.
- Worked on multilayered MVVM architectural pattern being extensively used in the application which helped to write scalable code.
- Followed guidelines for solid principles and clean code during the development.
- Knowledge of core concepts like Dependency Injection, OOPs, Data structure, and Core Data.
- Have worked on integrating third-party libraries in the application like Alamofire, MagicalRecord, and SkeletonView and managing them accordingly.
- Have worked in persisting data locally using Core Data and UserDefault.
- Have been actively involved in tech grooming and prd doubt discussion.
- Worked on writing complex business logic in an efficient way to incorporate all the business requirements.

Brain Tumour Detection

August 2020 - September 2020

- This project can detect whether a person have Brain Tumour or not, by analysing the MRI scan.
- Convolutional Neural Network is used to develop the model.
- Technology: Python, Machine Learning

Face Mask Detection

March 2020 - April 2020

- This project can detect whether a person wearing a mask or not in a video stream with accuracy by using Neural Network.
- Technology: Python, Machine Learning

Automated Teller Machine

October 2019 - November 2019

- This performs all the tasks of an ATM.
- **Technology**: Python, SQL, Tkinter

EDUCATION

Guru Tegh Bahadur Institute of Technology, New Delhi	2017 - 2021
Bachelor of Technology Information Technology Percentage: 77	
Gyan Sagar Public School, New Delhi	2017
12th CBSE Percentage: 78	
Kennedy Public School, New Delhi	2015
10th CBSE Percentage: 74	